(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ナイトループ
Mio 5th Anniversary Live
Night Loop
まもなく、大神ミオ5周年記念ライブ
『ナイトループ』スタートします。
Coming soon, Ookami Mio's 5th Anniversary Live
'Night Loop' will begin.
ライブのコンセプトはアルバムのテーマと同じ、
夜です。
The concept of this live is the same as
the album's theme: night.
ぜひ最後までごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Please relax and enjoy until the very end.
2018年から5年間...
Five years since 2018...
通り過ぎてきた、たくさんの夜。
So many nights have passed by.
長かったような、短かったような。
They felt long, yet short at the same time.
何度でも繰り返したいような...
Like something I'd want to repeat over and over...
繰り返したい。
I want to repeat them.
君はこのループから抜け出したいの？
Do you want to escape from this loop?
聴こえますか？
Can you hear me?
夜光通信
Night Light Communication
ハロー ハロー 聴こえますか
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
そっちは何年？
What year is it over there?
正しく分かち合う手段は
The ways to truly share ourselves...
一つじゃないさ
...aren't just one.
漂う時間は何処へ行くのか
Where does this drifting time go?
さよならはいつ誰が決めるの？
When and who decides our goodbyes?
その手に触れようと願ってる
I'm wishing to touch those hands.
本当さ
It's true.
永遠の夜光 君に歌う
Eternal night light, I sing for you.
世界中が君にいじわるでも
Even if the whole world is mean to you,
思い出して
Remember this,
覚えていて
keep it in mind.
瞼の裏 ずっとまた会えるからね
Behind your eyelids, we can always meet again.
穏やかに
Peacefully,
健やかに
healthily.
流れ続け 君だって私だって
Continuing to flow, both you and I...
消えるのは 言葉だけ
...the only things that disappear are words.
ふんわり君を抱きしめてあげるからね
I'll gently hold you close.
泣かないで
Don't cry.
延々と続く今日は
This today that goes on forever
雪原のようで
is like a snowy field.
当然の幸せすら
Even natural happiness...
夜光通信
Nightglow Communication
眩ませるんだ
I'll dazzle them
忘れないで
Don't forget
何処へだって繋がる回線
A circuit that connects anywhere
寂しい宇宙とオレンジの公園
A lonely universe and an orange park
慕わしい心の限りを
With all my yearning heart
歌おう
Let's sing
永遠の夜光
Eternal nightglow
届くよね
It will reach you, right?
幻想よりも優しいかたちのまま
In a form gentler than a fantasy
溢れそぼる
Overflowing and soaking
その頬を
Those cheeks
こっそり撫でて
Gently stroking them
乾かしてあげるからね
I'll dry them for you
何度だって
Again and again
永遠の夜光
Eternal nightglow
虚空に歌う
Singing to the void
会いたいよ
I want to see you
消えたくなんてないよ
I don't want to disappear
思い出して
Remember
覚えていて
Keep it in mind
今ここで
Right here, right now
笑い合ったことを
That we laughed together
永遠の夜光
Eternal nightglow
君に歌う
I sing to you
世界中が君に意地悪でも
Even if the whole world is mean to you
思い出して
Remember
覚えていて
Keep it in mind
瞼の裏
Behind your eyelids
ずっとまた会えるからね
We'll always be able to meet again
さよならは
Goodbye is...
ねえ誰が決めるもの
Hey, who gets to decide that?
消えるのは
What disappears is
言葉だけ
Only words
ほんのり君を
I'll softly
抱きしめてあげるからね
Hold you close
泣かないで
Please don't cry
永遠の銀
ー 祈 ー
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Eternal Silver
- Prayer -
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Shota Horie
残された呼吸を
If I use up
使い果たせば
The breath left in me
抱きとめた記憶さえ
Even the memories I held onto
灰へと散る
Will scatter into ash
鼓動とは呪いだと
Knowing that my heartbeat is a curse
気づきながら
Knowing this very well
惨めさを笑い行く
I go on laughing at the misery
うつろな響き
A hollow sound
その叫びもやがて過去に溶ける
That scream, too, will eventually melt into the past
暗室の花だけを道連れに
With only the flowers of the darkroom as companions
嫌だよ終わるために生まれた悲劇など
I hate it—a tragedy born just to end
息を止めて
Holding my breath
そのままで
Just as I am
命よ銀に光れ
O life, shine in silver
果てなき夢が
May the endless dream
いつまでも続きますように
Continue forever
消えたくないよ
I don't want to disappear
消えないで
Don't disappear
ただそれだけを祈った
That's all I prayed for
最後の最後の幸せ
The very last happiness
誰にも誰にも奪わせない
I won't let anyone, anyone take it away
離さない
I won't let go
造られた世界は
I wonder which one
どちらだろうか
The created world is
目を背け死神に
Turning my eyes away
買われたのは
And being bought by the Grim Reaper
揺れる火の鮮やかさを持て囃す頃
As they praise the brightness of the flickering fire
白蝋は泣き続ける
The white wax keeps on weeping
その結末を思い出せ
Remember that ending
朝を迎えるのは
How many days left
あと何日だろう
Until morning comes?
許された時間は
How many minutes left
あと何分だろう
Of the time I'm allowed?
この心が満たされるのは
How many seconds left
あと何秒だろう
Until this heart is filled?
怖いよ
I'm scared
届かずに
Of the day it reaches the end
朽ちてゆくその日が
And rots away without reaching anything
息を止めて
Holding my breath
そのままで
Just as I am
命よ銀に光れ
O life, shine in silver
優しい歌が
May the gentle song
いつまでも響きますように
Echo forever
哀しみもいつか去るのなら
If sorrow too will someday pass
いつかまでを繰り返した
I've repeated "until someday" over and over
こんなにこんなに鮮やかだ
It's so, so vivid
最後の最後の願い事
The very last wish
安らかなる日々だけが続けばよかった
I wish those peaceful days could have just continued...
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I'd had the strength just to protect them...
静かな夕凪をずっと見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching that quiet evening calm forever...
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I'd had the strength just to protect it...
安らかなる日々だ
It was a peaceful time.
静かな夕凪をずっと見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the quiet evening calm forever.
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect it.
安らかなる日々だけが続けばよかった
I wish only the peaceful days would continue.
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect it.
すべてを捧げても
Even if I offer everything.
息を止めて そのままで 命よ銀に光れ
Hold your breath, just like that. Life, shine in silver.
果てなき夢が いつまでも 続きますように
May the endless dream continue forever.
消えたくないよ 消えないで ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to disappear, don't disappear. I just prayed for that.
最後の 最後の 幸せ
The final, final happiness.
それでも それでも 触れるなら
Even so, even so, if I can touch it...
許さない
I won't allow it.
雨、やまないなー
The rain won't stop...
ミオちゃーん！
Mio-chaan!
あやめ！こんなとこでなにしてんの？
Ayame! What are you doing in a place like this?
あやめこそ、こんなとこで会うなんて奇遇だね。
Same to you, what a coincidence to meet in a place like this.
雨、やまないね。
The rain isn't stopping, is it?
そうだね。
Yeah.
雨だけど、ミオちゃんに会えて嬉しいな。
It's raining, but I'm glad I could see you, Mio-chan.
あやめ、なんかあった？
Ayame, did something happen?
なんもないよ。
Nothing's wrong.
うそうそ。うちもあやめに会えて嬉しいよ。
No way. I'm glad to see you too, Ayame.
もうちょっとお話ししたいな。
I want to talk a bit more.
うん。
Yeah.
あぁ全然できてないな…
Ah, I'm not ready at all...
漏らす吐息、溜息
Letting out breaths and sighs.
雨音響いていく 午前0時
The sound of rain echoing, 12 AM.
明けなき夜 願っている
Wishing for a night that never ends.
少しだけこのままで
Just for a little while, like this.
ココロ、夜と雨の中
My heart is in the night and the rain.
揺れる想い まだ整理途中
Swaying feelings, still sorting them out.
流れる時間の中
In the passing time.
明日晴れたらいいな
I hope it's sunny tomorrow.
そんな些細な
Such a trivial...
願いごとカタチにして 集めよう
...wish, let's give it shape and gather them.
夜照らすムーンライト
Moonlight illuminating the night.
空を泳ぐ 顔上げて前へ
Swimming through the sky, look up and move forward.
踏み出してこう
Let's step out.
夜と雨の先
Beyond the night and rain.
出口は、まだ
The exit is still...
あぁ全然変わらないな…
Ah, nothing has changed at all...
漏れる軽い微笑み
A light smile escaping.
液晶見つめる 午前3時
Staring at the screen, 3 AM.
楽しいコト 悲しいコト
Happy things, sad things.
ひとつに丸めちゃって
Roll them all into one.
夜の中に置いておくの
And leave them in the night.
「頑張ろう」とか 「できるよ」とか
Like "Let's do our best" or "You can do it."
無責任な言葉たち 嫌になるから
Because I'm sick of those irresponsible words.
真っすぐに進みたいよ
I want to move straight ahead.
流れる時間の中
In the passing time.
駆けだす
Running out.
明日会えたらどんな
If we meet tomorrow, what kind of...
顔するかな
...face will you make?
朝日みたいな笑顔で 迎えて
Welcome me with a smile like the morning sun.
夜照らすムーンライト
Moonlight illuminating the night.
街を眺む
Looking over the town,
悩みすら全部 見透かすように
even all my worries, as if seeing through them.
降り止まないまま
As it continues to rain.
今も 夜明けは まだ
Still, the dawn is yet to come...
Lalala...
窓に映る景色 雨は宝石で
The scenery in the window, rain like jewels
夜空は 黒いドレスのように 煌めいて
The night sky, sparkling like a black dress
私を照らす
Illuminating me
夜は明けないから
Because the night doesn't break
まだ この夜が好きだから
Because I still love this night
夜と雨に
In the night and rain
包まれていく ああ
Being enveloped, ah...
明日晴れたらいいな
I hope it's sunny tomorrow
そんな些細な
Such a small
願い事カタチにして
Wishing for it to take shape
集めよう
Let's gather them
夜照らすムーンライト
Moonlight illuminating the night
空を泳ぐ
Swimming in the sky
顔上げて前へ
Lift your head and move forward
踏み出してこう
Let's step out
君と一緒なら
If I'm with you
越えたいから
Because I want to overcome it
音楽でも
Even through music
夜と雨の先
Beyond the night and rain
明けたら、ほら
When it dawns, look...
カメリア
Camelia
作詞・作曲：川江美奈子 編曲：村田昭
Lyrics/Composition: Minako Kawae, Arrangement: Akira Murata
ここはどこ
Where is this?
あたたかい雪が降る
Warm snow is falling
不思議な場所
A mysterious place
デジャヴみたい
Like déjà vu
真っ白な夜
A pure white night
ぽつりと咲いている
Blooming all alone
紅い頬の
With red cheeks
私見つけて
Find me
つかれたね かなしいね
It was tiring, wasn't it? It was sad, wasn't it?
もうやめたいね
You want to stop now, don't you?
でもふりしぼって
But wringing it out
私へと辿りついてくれて
Reaching me at last
ありがとう
Thank you
あなたを待っていたの
I was waiting for you
ずっとここで
All this time, right here
世界が目覚めても
Even if the world wakes up
そばにいさせて
Let me be by your side
あなたのために咲くよ
I will bloom for you
ずっとここで
All this time, right here
春に追いつくされても
Even if springtime catches up
覚えていて
Please remember
いつのまにか
Before I knew it
泣き方も忘れてた
I had even forgotten how to cry
空っぽの箱
An empty box
ひとりきりだった
I was all alone
さみしくて 折れそうで
Lonely, about to break
傷ついても愛してしまうの
I end up loving, even if I get hurt
諦めず探していてくれて
For never giving up and looking for me
ありがとう
Thank you
あなたを待っていたの
I was waiting for you
ずっとここで
All this time, right here
覚えていて
Please remember
ひらひら舞い降りる雪が
The snow falling and dancing about
やさしいね
Is so gentle
いまこの瞬間
This very moment
しあわせと名づけさせて
Let me name it happiness
あなたのために咲くよ
I will bloom for you
ずっとここで
All this time, right here
春に追いつくされても
Even if springtime catches up
覚えていて
Please remember
ここに咲いてること
That I am blooming here...
覚えていて
...please remember it.
君に出会うことができて本当に良かった。
I'm so glad I could meet you.
これからも君の居場所になれるように
So that I can continue to be your place to belong...
いつでもふと思い出してもらえるように
...so that you can remember me anytime...
ホロライブで咲き続けるからね
...I'll keep blooming in Hololive.
ねえ、今日が何の日か覚えてる？
Hey, do you remember what day it is today?
そう、うちがホロライブで活動始めて5年経ったんだよ。
That's right, it's been 5 years since I started in Hololive.
うーん、色んなことがあったけど、
Hmm, a lot of things happened, but...
楽しかったなって思うことの方が多かったかな。
...I think there were more times I thought it was fun.
本当だよ。君にも出会うことができたしね。
It's true. I was able to meet you, too.
え、もう行っちゃうの？
Eh, are you leaving already?
そっか、君にも色々あるよね。
I see, you have various things going on too.
でも大丈夫。
But it's okay.
またきっと会えるよ。
I'm sure we'll meet again.
幽霊東京
Yuurei Tokyo
作詞・作曲・編曲：Ayase
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Ayase
燦々と輝く街の明かり
The town lights shining brilliantly
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down at me in contrast
あのビルの間を抜けて
Passing between those buildings
色付き出したネオンと混じって
Mingling with the neon lights that have begun to color
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード
Trading my time with this world
夜に沈む
Sinking into the night
終電で家路を辿る僕の目に映る
Reflected in my eyes as I make my way home on the last train
ガラス窓にいたのは夢見た自分じゃなくて
In the glass window wasn't the me I dreamed of
今にも泣き出してしまいそうな
Looking like I'm about to burst into tears
暗闇の中一人彷徨っている
Wandering alone in the darkness
哀しい人
A sad person
「大丈夫、いつか大丈夫になる」なんて思う日々を
Days of thinking "It's okay, someday it'll be okay"
いくつか重ねた
Piled up a few of them
今日だって一人東京の景色に透ける僕は
Even today, alone, I'm transparent against the Tokyo scenery
幽霊みたいだ
Like a ghost
失うことに慣れていく中で
As I get used to losing things
忘れてしまったあの願いさえも
Even those wishes I had forgotten
思い出した時に涙が落ちたのは
The reason tears fell when I remembered
この街がただ
Is just that this town...
あまりにも眩しいから
...is just too bright
「散々だ」って笑いながら嘆く
Lamenting "It's terrible" while laughing
ハイテクな日々の中の火の思いがフラッシュバック
Memories of those days flash back in these high-tech days
気付けば朝まで開くロジック
Before I knew it, logic opens until morning
僕の言葉を音に乗せて何度も
Putting my words to sound over and over
失うことに慣れていく中で
As I get used to losing things
忘れてしまったあの日々でさえも
Even those days I had forgotten
それでもまだ先へなんて思えるのは
The reason I can still think about moving forward
君がいるから
Is because you are here
ねえ
Hey...
こんな寂しい街で
In such a lonely town...
ねえ
Hey...
燦々と輝く街の明かり
The town lights shining brilliantly
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down at me in contrast
あのビルの先で手を伸ばして
Reaching out beyond those buildings
あの日夢見た景色を望んで
Wishing for the scenery I dreamed of that day
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード
Trading my time with this world
明日を呼ぶ
Calling tomorrow
失うことに慣れていく中で
As I get used to losing things
失くさずにいた大事な思いを
Those precious feelings I didn't lose
抱きしめたら不意に涙が落ちたのは
When I embraced them, tears suddenly fell because...
この街でまだ生きてたいと思うから
...I want to keep living in this town
君もそうでしょう
You feel the same, right?
夜明けのメロウ
Yoake no Mellow
真夜中流れていく
Flowing through the midnight,
ビルをなぞって
tracing the buildings
消える
and fading away.
どこへゆくの？
Where are you going?
変わってゆくこと
Realizing that things are changing,
気づいて　立ちどまった
I came to a standstill.
曖昧で不確かなもの
Vague and uncertain things,
終わりあることだから
because they have an end,
私は此処にある
I am here.
君といる時間の中で
In the time I spend with you,
呼吸をするんでしょう
I'll take a breath, right?
変わらないで、と
"Please don't change,"
終わらないで、と
"Please don't end."
今日も夜明けを呑む
Again today, I swallow the dawn.
輝いていたい
I want to shine.
こんな世界で歌う私を
The me who sings in this kind of world,
どうか殺さないで
please, don't kill her.
君の隣で溶けて消えるまで
Until I melt and vanish by your side,
生きて
I'll live.
揺らいだ切なさは
The wavering sadness
いつかの朝に似てる
resembles a morning long ago.
ひとりじゃない
I'm not alone.
眩しさの中
In the midst of the brightness,
確かに触れた
I certainly felt it.
心の片隅
In a corner of my heart,
君の瞳に映る私を
The me reflected in your eyes,
焼き付けて
burn it into your memory.
その手で抱きしめて
Hold me with those hands.
きっと誰よりも強く輝けるでしょう
I'm sure I can shine brighter than anyone else.
変わりゆくもの　終わりゆくもの
Things that change, things that end,
ひとつ　瞬くように
each like a single blink.
確かめていたい
I want to make sure.
霞む世界に歌う私を
The me who sings in a hazy world,
どうか忘れないで
please, don't forget her.
君の記憶の底へ淡く甘く
Deep into your memories, faintly and sweetly,
滲んで　ひとつになって
blurring, and becoming one,
漂うだけ
simply drifting.
泣き出しそうな
Ready to burst into tears,
夜の隙間を縫って
threading through the gaps in the night,
私はゆく　夜明けのメロウ
I will go, dawn's mellow.
君の隣で溶けて消えるほど
Enough to melt and vanish by your side,
生きて
I'll live.
待ってたよね、
You were waiting,
たくさん。
a lot.
うちさ、1stアルバムが
You know, when it was decided
出せるってなった時、
that I could release my 1st album,
相当嬉しかったんだよ。
I was so incredibly happy.
歌うことは大好きだったけど、
I loved singing, but
自信が正直なかったから。
honestly, I didn't have much confidence.
もう、これ以上うまく歌えることは
I thought to myself that I wouldn't be able
ないだろうなって、
to sing any better than this,
勝手に思っちゃっててさ。
just assuming that was the case.
でもね、
But, you see,
君が待っててくれたから。
because you were waiting for me.
うまくならないって思ってたのに、
Even though I thought I wouldn't improve,
なんか成長したなって思うんだよね。
I feel like I've grown somehow.
より一層、歌が好きになれたんだ。
I've come to love singing even more.
気づかせてくれたのは、
The one who made me realize that
君だよ。
was you.
深く紺になる
Fukaku Kon ni Naru
どこまで行こうか　ネイビーな夜空に
How far shall we go? Reflecting in the navy night sky,
映る昨日の自分
is yesterday's self.
夢見がちだった
I was prone to dreaming.
ベイビーデイズにサヨナラ
Goodbye to the baby days
見たくないもの照らすハイビームに
In the high beams illuminating things I don't want to see
走る焦燥感
Runs a sense of impatience
跳ね除けて前へ行けば
If I push it aside and move forward
信号は皆 色を無くし消えた
All the traffic lights lost their color and vanished
確かめたい
I want to confirm
この道が繋ぐ先を
Where this road leads
深く深く紺になる
It becomes a deep, deep navy
夜を往けるこの加速度
This acceleration that lets me go through the night
光さえ超えてゆける程に
To the point where I can even surpass light
強く強く踏み込んで
Stepping on it strongly, strongly
僕は駆けるただ真っ直ぐに
I dash, just straight ahead
譲れない想いを抱いて
Embracing feelings I won't give up
標識だらけの街を抜け出して
Breaking out of the city full of signs
明日を探してた
I was searching for tomorrow
常識も何も全部雑音と化してた
Common sense and everything else had turned into noise
「何処まで行けるの？」なんて聞き飽きた台詞吐いて
Spitting out lines I'm tired of hearing, like "How far can you go?"
曇った窓ガラスに書いた本音
The true feelings I wrote on the fogged window
すぐに指で消した
I quickly erased with my finger
臆病でも
Even if I'm a coward
揺るぎない軌跡
An unwavering trajectory
確かな願いを
With a certain wish
胸に遥か遠く
In my heart, far away
錆び付くように軋んでも
Even if it creaks as if rusting
この真っ暗を灯し進む
I move forward, lighting up this darkness
たった一つ答えを追いかけて
Chasing after the only one answer
脆くても良いこの腕で
Even if they're fragile, with these arms
掴む為に手を伸ばすよ
I'll reach out to grab it
打ち鳴らす鼓動の限り
As long as my heart beats
何度この道で迷って
How many times have I been lost on this road
見失ってどこへ行くの
Lost my way, where am I going?
目指す場所もその意味も
The place I'm aiming for and its meaning
一つしか無いのにな
There is only one, though
曇った視界は
My clouded vision
夜に溶けてもう一度
Dissolves into the night once more
ひらけてゆく
And starts to clear up
視線の先
At the end of my gaze
僕を連れてゆくよきっと
It will surely take me there
深く深く紺になる
It becomes a deep, deep navy
息を吸って今加速を
Take a breath, and now, acceleration
傷付くほどに強くなると
As I become stronger the more I get hurt
確かな色動き出す
A certain color starts to move
纏ってゆけその身体で
Wear it with that body
鮮やかな夜空の果てへ
To the end of the vivid night sky
忘れないように
So I don't forget
深く深く紺になれ
Become a deep, deep navy
今を生きるこの加速度
This acceleration that lives in the now
光だって超えてゆける場所へ
To a place where I can even surpass light
強く強く踏み込んで
Stepping on it strongly, strongly
僕を駆けるただ真っ直ぐに
I dash through, just straight ahead
譲れない想いを抱いて
Embracing feelings I won't give up
止まらないで
Don't stop
走り続ける意味を知るから
Because I know the meaning of continuing to run
わくわくエブリデイ
Waku Waku Everyday
心地よい晴れ空
A pleasant clear sky
今日は何をして遊ぼうか
What should we do for fun today?
いつまでも変わらない
Never changing
雲を追いかけてみようか
Shall we try chasing the clouds?
はしゃぎ回って疲れて
Frolicking around and getting tired
お腹もすいて寝転んで
Getting hungry and lying down
明日はもっといい日になりそう
It looks like tomorrow will be an even better day
一緒だよ
We're together
いつもキラキラ毎日止まらないでしょ
Every day is always sparkling, it won't stop, right?
やりたいこと全部遊び尽くしても
Even if we play through everything we want to do
...やりたいこと全部遊び尽くしても
...Even if we play through everything we want to do
今はまだ知らないこと沢山あるけど
There are still many things we don't know yet
君と君と手を取って
Holding hands with you, with you
ずっと笑えるといいよね
It would be nice if we could keep laughing forever, wouldn't it?
朝まで喋り込んで 眠くなる日もあったよね
There were days we talked until morning and got sleepy, weren't there?
些細な悩みさえも 笑いに変えてくれたよね
You even turned my minor worries into laughter, didn't you?
たまに怒ってうつむいて
Sometimes getting angry, looking down
励まし合って乗り越えて
Encouraging each other and overcoming it
一人じゃできないことでも
Even things I can't do alone
二人なら
If we're together...
ほらね？ワクワクすること 止まらないでしょ
See? The excitement doesn't stop, does it?
やりたいこと叶える力があるよ
We have the power to make our wishes come true
そうでしょ？ときめくココロに色づく毎日
Right? Every day colored by a racing heart
君と君と手を取って
Holding hands with you, with you
「今」を重ね続けてこう
Let's keep piling up "nows"
笑顔の帰り道も
Even the way home with a smile
何年経っても
No matter how many years pass
君となら ずっと...
If it's with you, always...
いつまでだって続くんだ
It will go on forever
どこまでだって行けそうだ
I feel like I can go anywhere
友達なんて言葉じゃもう足りないよ
The word "friends" isn't enough anymore
いつもそばで支えててくれてありがとう
Thank you for always being by my side and supporting me
一緒に笑い合ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for laughing together with me
今はまだ知らないこと沢山あるけど
There are still many things we don't know yet
君と君と手を取って
Holding hands with you, with you
転んで泣きそうな時も
Even when I fall and am about to cry
君と君と明日も
With you, with you, tomorrow too
ずっと笑えるといいよね
It would be nice if we could keep laughing forever, wouldn't it?
これからも
From now on too
よろしくどうぞ
Pleased to meet you
皆さんお待たせ！
Everyone, thanks for waiting!
活動5周年記念フルセット！
The 5th Anniversary Full Set!
記念グッズはこちらとなっております！
Here are the anniversary goods!
活動5周年記念フルセット
5th Anniversary Full Set
はい、こんな感じのフルセットですね。
Yes, here's the full set.
いやー、泉彩パパのイラストが今回も光っております。
Wow, Izumi Sai-papa's illustration is shining this time too.
では1個ずつグッズを紹介させてもらいます。
Now, let me introduce each item one by one.
まずは、泉彩パパ描き下ろしのパブミラー！
First, the pub mirror drawn by Izumi Sai-papa!
パブミラー
Pub Mirror
パブミラーって一体なんだ？って
I think many people are wondering
思ってる人も結構多いと思うんですけれども、
what on earth a "pub mirror" is, but...
パブミラーは、うーん、イラストの背景がなんか鏡になってて、
A pub mirror, well, the background of the illustration is a mirror,
高級感があって、特別な感じの、えーとインテリアみたいな感じなのかな。
it has a high-quality, special feel, I guess it's like interior decor.
で、今回、アクリルスタンドとはまた別に、
And this time, separate from the acrylic stand,
高級感、特別感を出したくて、パブミラーを出してみました。
I wanted to bring out a sense of luxury and specialness, so I tried a pub mirror.
皆さんの、おうちに飾ってみてください。
Please try decorating your home with it.
そしてお次が、ミオしゃとお出かけコインケース！
And next is the "Outing with Mio-sha Coin Case"!
ミオしゃとお出かけコインケース
Outing with Mio-sha Coin Case
こちらは、みんながイベントに行くときに、
I thought everyone uses coins a lot
よくこうコインをね、使うんじゃないかと思って、
when they go to events, so...
そのコインを出し入れするためだけのコインケースがあったら
I thought it would be convenient to have a coin case
便利なんじゃないかなと思い、作ってみました。
just for taking those coins in and out, so I made one.
このコインケースと一緒にイベントに行ってくれたら、うちはとっても嬉しいな。
I'd be very happy if you went to events with this coin case.
はい、ではお次。ミオしゃ思い出フォトフレーム！
Yes, next. The "Mio-sha Memories Photo Frame"!
ミオしゃ思い出フォトフレーム
Mio-sha Memories Photo Frame
こちらは、うちがいつも特典でつけてるポストカードと、
For this one, I made a photo frame that's just right
を入れるのにちょうどいい感じのフォトフレームを作ってみました。
for putting in the postcards I always include as bonuses.
うーん、またね、このしかたない先生の描き下ろしなんですけど、
Again, these are illustrations by Shikata Nai-sensei.
コインケースもね、描き下ろしていただいたんですが、とっても可愛いですね。
The coin case was also drawn by them, and it's very cute.
ぜひぜひこちらのなかにポストカードを飾って、
Please, please, display your postcards inside this
おうちで眺めてみてくださいね。
and enjoy looking at them at home.
はい、そして最後が、ミオファの森の住民カード！
Yes, and finally, the "Miofa Forest Resident Card"!
ミオファの森の住民カード
Miofa Forest Resident Card
こちらはですね、ミオファの森の住民のみんなが、
For this one, I made it so all the residents of the Miofa Forest
うん、ミオファの森内での、えー身分証明に使えるように作ってみました。
can use it as identification within the Miofa Forest.
何言ってんだろ。
What am I even saying?
よく分からないと思うけどねー
I'm sure you don't really get it, though.
はい、ちなみにシリアル番号は、えっと、それぞれ入っているんですけれど...
Yes, and by the way, there's a serial number on each one...
えー、シリアル番号全員が違うので
...and since every serial number is different...
世界に一つだけ、一枚だけのカードとなっておりますので
...it's a one-of-a-kind card in the whole world.
ぜひ、ミオファのみんなはゲットしてみてください
So, all you Miofa, please try to get one.
そして、最後にこのグッズのフルセット...
And finally, if you buy the full set of these goods...
買ってもらうと特典が二つあります！
...you'll get two special bonuses!
大神ミオ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り
An Ookami Mio hand-signed and foil-stamped message...
泉パパ描き下ろしのポストカード！イェーイ！長い長い！
...postcard illustrated by Izumi-papa! Yay! That's a long name!
えっと、うちが直筆のサインを入れて...
Um, I'll be putting my autograph on it...
さらに箔押しの、箔押しじゃない、箔押しのメッセージが入った
...and it'll also have a foil-stamped message...
ポストカードとなっております
...on the postcard.
泉パパのイラストで、さっきのパブミラーのイラストなんだけど
The illustration is by Izumi-papa, the same one as the pub mirror...
ちょっと差分で表情が違ったりするので
...but the expression is slightly different, so...
ぜひぜひ、こちらも手に入れてください
...please, definitely get this too.
そしてお次が、特典二つ目！
And next up is the second bonus!
特典ボイス『5周年の後も君と一緒に』というテーマで
A special voice clip with the theme "Together with you even after the 5th anniversary"...
シチュエーションボイスを撮らせていただきました
...I've recorded a situation voice clip.
ま、ちょっといつもね、ボイス撮るの少し恥ずかしいんだけれども
Well, you know, I always find it a bit embarrassing to record these voice clips...
5年間一緒に過ごしてくれたみんなに感謝の気持ちを込めて
...but with feelings of gratitude for everyone who has spent these five years with me...
シチュエーションボイス、台本から考えたので
...I even thought up the script myself, so...
ぜひぜひ、ちょっと小っ恥ずかしいですが聴いてください
...even though it's a bit awkward, please give it a listen.
さて、グッズ告知も終わったね
Well, that's the end of the goods announcement.
けど、なんか物足りないなー
But I feel like something is missing.
君もなんか短いなって思ってない？
Don't you feel like it was a bit short too?
あー、そっか
Ah, I see.
物足りないなら、もう一回5年目いっとく？
If it's not enough, shall we go through the 5th year again?
ここだけの話
Just between you and me...
ライブのタイトルの『ナイトループ』ってあるじゃん？
You know how the title of this live is "Night Loop"?
あれって気づいてたかもしれないけど、曲名なんだよね
You might have already noticed, but that's actually the name of a song.
この夢のようなライブが終わった後に
After this dream-like live is over...
なんとMVも公開されちゃいます！
...believe it or not, the MV will be released!
じゃあ、心の準備はいい？いくよ！
So, are you ready? Here we go!
ナイトループ！
Night Loop!
相も変わらず上ばかり見ておかしくなる
As always, I'm just looking up and going crazy
やる気は減っていく
My motivation is fading away
昨日に賭けっこ明日に背を向け
Betting on yesterday, turning my back on tomorrow
入れ褪せた過去とやり合ってんだ
Fighting with a faded past
抑えつけるほどに嵩を増していく
The more I suppress it, the more it grows
劣等感その多寡諸々
Feelings of inferiority and so on
溺れる前に夜を染め上げなきゃ
I must dye the night before I drown
粋じゃないポーズ決め込んで
Striking an uncool pose
不満さっぽけ詰め込んで
Stuffing away my tiny frustrations
叩き割ったらバフ一つまた一つ
Once broken, I get one buff after another
飲み込めないくらい
So much that I can't swallow it all
ほら喰れてやるよクエを全部
Look, I'll devour it all, every single quest
ちゃんと噛んで味わいながら
Chewing properly and savoring the taste
感想聞いてみてもいいですか？
Can I ask for your thoughts?
僕ら灰を背負ったままナイトループだ
We're in a night loop, carrying the ashes
そう壊れるまで
Until we break
愛をギュッとしたサイコーループだ
It's a psycho loop, squeezed with love
もう縛れないよ
I can't be tied down anymore
正解すら間違っているんだ そうだろう
Even the right answers are wrong. Isn't that right?
誰も彼もバカみたい
Everyone and everything is like a fool
イタイの飛んでいけナイトループだ
Pain, pain, go away, it's a night loop
そう足掻けるまで
Until we can struggle
やいのやいのどうしようもないから
Since there's no helping the noise and chatter
もう騙らないで
Don't deceive me anymore
あと少しで絶望と希望の境界線
Just a bit more until the border of despair and hope
背伸びすれば届きそうな称賛
Praise that seems reachable if I stretch
脱線したい
I want to derail
うわって声漏らしちゃって目を逸らしちゃって
Letting out a "Whoa" and looking away
凹み散らかすまでがワンセット
Getting depressed is all part of the set
やる気あんで毎日にニュな 己のバースデー
Got motivation, every day is a new birthday for myself
諦めても諦めなくても
Whether I give up or not
僕を置いて進んでく時間
Time keeps moving forward, leaving me behind
抜け出せないなら乗るしかないじゃん しょうがないなあ
If I can't escape, I just have to ride along. Well, can't be helped.
沸いてこうぜほらナイトループだ
Let's get hyped, look, it's a night loop
もう止まらないね
It won't stop now
変になったのはどっちなんだか さあ分からないね
Which one of us has gone strange? Well, I don't know.
明後日前で巻き戻したいの延長戦
Wanting to rewind from the day after tomorrow, extra time
一か八か散か夜か 最後に笑うためだ
All or nothing, scattered or night. It's so I can laugh at the end.
好きなだけ泣いて抗おうか
Shall we cry as much as we want and resist?
妄想の自分が未来から手を振っている
My delusional self is waving from the future
行こうぞ最果ての先へ アンハッピー
Let's go, beyond the very end. Unhappy.
まだ夜は明けない 煙るネオンサイン
The night hasn't ended yet. Smoky neon sign.
不安掻き消そうぜ
Let's drown out the anxiety
まだ夢は冷めない 嗤うギミックノイズ
The dream hasn't cooled down yet. Sneering gimmick noise.
今打ち消そうぜ
Let's negate it now
僕ら灰を背負ったままナイトループだ
We're in a night loop, carrying the ashes
そう壊れるまで
Until we break
愛をギュッとしたサイコーループだ
It's a psycho loop, squeezed with love
もう縛れないよ
I can't be tied down anymore
正解すら間違っているんだ そうだろう
Even the right answers are wrong. Isn't that right?
誰も彼もバカみたい
Everyone and everything is like a fool
イタイの飛んでいけナイトループだ
Pain, pain, go away, it's a night loop
そう足掻けるまで
Until we can struggle
やいのやいのどうしようもないから
Since there's no helping the noise and chatter
もう踊らないで
Don't dance anymore
あと少しで
In just a bit longer
絶望と希望の境界線
The boundary between despair and hope
背伸びすれば届きそうな
As if I could reach it if I stood on my toes
情景
The scene
うだうだ
Uda uda
脱線したい
I want to derail
ループ
Loop
2018年から5年間
Five years since 2018.
通り過ぎてきた、たくさんの夜
The many nights that have passed by.
長かったような、短かったような
Seemingly long, yet seemingly short.
何度でも、繰り返したいような
The kind of nights I'd want to repeat over and over again.
繰り返したい...
I want to repeat...
君は、このループから抜け出したい？
Do you want to break out of this loop?
君は、このループを抜け出すことを選んだんだね
So you chose to break out of this loop.
そっか
I see.
じゃあ、うちと
Well then, with me,
6年目を始めよう
let's start our sixth year.
なんだかワクワクしてきた
I'm starting to get excited.
最後に、もう一曲だけ
Just one last song.
アンコール
Encore.
聞いてね
Please listen.
Sirius
作詞：MegRi 作曲：Nika Lenz 編曲：水野谷怜
Lyrics: MegRi Composition: Nika Lenz Arrangement: Mizunoya Rei
ごめんね　ありがとう
I'm sorry, thank you
声にしてみても
Even if I put it into words
届かない　戻らない
They don't reach, they won't return
あの日の僕らは
We from those days
かじかむ手繋いで
Holding our numbed hands
朝に怯えて　震えていた
Frightened by the morning, we were shivering
失くさないでと　消えないでと
Saying "don't lose it" and "don't disappear"
願っても
Even if I pray
色褪せてゆく　記憶のかけら
The fragments of memory continue to fade
抱きしめ　眠るよ
I'll hold them tight and sleep
「会いたい」ただ、願うほどに
"I want to see you", the more I just pray
目閉じて　覚めない夢の中
I close my eyes in a dream I won't wake from
いつかの　君を　探してる
I'm searching for you from some day
僕はまだ　あの夜を一人
I still, through that night alone...
歩こう
...will walk
呼吸も　温度も
Breath and temperature too
失くした世界に
In a world where they've been lost
約束は　今も
The promise is, even now
美しいままで
Still as beautiful as ever
夜空に咲いている
Blooming in the night sky
君の声だけ　聞こえないよ
Only your voice is inaudible
ここにいるのに　叫ぶのに
Even though I'm here, even though I'm shouting
夜はまた　隠してしまう
The night hides it away again
優しい嘘で　包んで
Wrap it in a gentle lie
溶かして
And melt it
「またあした」も、言えないまま
Still unable to even say "see you tomorrow"
彼方へとゆく　君を想うよ
I think of you, heading off to the distance
もう一度　だけ　笑いかけて
Smile at me just one more time
きっとまた　それだけで、僕は
Surely, with just that alone, I...
止まっていた　季節が解けるように
...as if the stopped seasons are thawing
やがて　夜は明けるから
Because before long, the night will break
動き出す　時が二人を分かつ
The time that starts moving will part us
遠く離れても　心は
Even if we are far apart, our hearts...
繋げて
...will be connected
さよなら
Farewell.
こぼれた涙は
The tears that overflowed
君がゆく あの空を飾るよ
will adorn the sky you travel to.
迷わないように
So that you don't get lost,
輝いてて
keep on shining.
いつまでも 忘れない 君を
I'll never forget you,
想うよ
I'm thinking of you.
明日も
Tomorrow too,
歌うよ
I'll sing.
明日は
Tomorrow...
逢いたい 願うほどに
The more I wish I could see you,
僕らまた 巡り合う 今で
the more we meet again in this moment.
おやすみ
Goodnight.
相変わらず上ばかり見て おかしくなるやりきれなさ 持っていく
Looking up as always, carrying the unbearable feeling that's driving me crazy.
責任かけっこ 焦りに背を向け 色褪せた過去とやり合ってんだ
Playing tag with responsibility, turning my back on impatience, I'm struggling with the faded past.
押さえつけるほどに嵩を増していく 劣等感その他諸々
The more I suppress it, the more it grows: inferiority complex and all that.
溺れる前に夜を染め上げなきゃ
Before I drown, I must dye the night.
敵じゃない方で決め込んで 不満散歩詰め込んで
Assuming it's not the enemy, stuffing in my walking dissatisfaction.
叩き割ったらバカ増える ひとつも ひとつも 飲み込めないくらい
If I smash it, fools increase, to the point I can't swallow even one, not even one.
ほら暮れてやるよ 悔いも全部 ちゃんと噛んで味わいながら
Look, I'll give it to you, all the regrets, while chewing and tasting them properly.
感想聞いてみてもいいですか か か
Can I ask for your thoughts?
期待飛んでいけないグループだ そう上がれるまで
It's a group where expectations can't fly away, yeah, until we can rise.
嫌い嫌いもどうしようもないから もう飾らないで
Since hate is unavoidable, don't dress it up anymore.
あと少しで届く希望の境界線
The borderline of hope that's just a little bit further.
背伸びすれば届きそうな頂上さ
A summit that seems reachable if I stretch.
いつも応援してくれている ミオファのみんな 本当にありがとう
To all the Miofa who always support me, thank you so much.
5周年ありがとう！！
Thank you for the 5th anniversary!!
ここまでとても短く感じた位、駆け抜けた5年間でした。
It's been a 5-year sprint, feeling so short until now.
今、私がホロライブに居られるのは君の応援があったお陰だよ。
The reason I can be in Hololive now is thanks to your support.
本当に、ありがとう。
Truly, thank you.
これからもいっぱい、一緒に楽しもうね♡
From now on, let's have fun together a lot, okay?
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio